Guide to the Frank Clyde Brown papers, 1912-1974 RL.00160
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Personal Papers, 1912-1974; 1
  - Folklore Collection Subseries, 3
    - Simpkins, [?] (Box 13)
    - Simpson, Eleanor (Box 13)
    - Sinclair, Mildred (Box 13)
    - Skinner, Charles (Box 13)
    - Sloan, Louise (Box 13)
    - Smith, Alphonso (Box 13)
    - Smith, Arthur (Box 13)
    - Smith, C. H. (Box 13)
    - Smith, Duo K. (Box 13)
    - Smith, Ella (Box 13)
    - Smith, Eunice (Box 13)
    - Smith, Helen (Box 13)
    - Smith, Lizzie (Box 13)
    - Smith, Merle (Box 13)
    - Smith, Sadie (Box 13)
    - Smith, Thomas, 3 folders (Box 14)
    - Smith, W. H. (Box 14)
    - Smith, W. O. (Box 14)
    - Smith, W. S. (Box 14)
    - Smithere, Lucy (Box 14)
    - Smothers, P. (Box 14)
    - Sneed, James (Box 14)
    - Snow, Annabel (Box 14)
    - Sondley, F. A. (Box 14)
    - Spence, W. E. (Box 14)
    - Spivey, E. B. (Box 14)
    - Stack, N. L. (Box 14)
    - Steinback, Albert (Box 14)
    - Stamey, Eph (Box 14)
    - Stanford, W. J. (Box 14)
    - Stanley, Fred (Box 14)
    - Starr, E. L. (Box 14)
    - Stephens, Erwin D. (Box 14)
    - Stinson, Fred (Box 14)
    - Stone, Alma (Box 14)
    - Strawbridge, Mary (Box 14)
    - Suchers, [?] (Box 14)
    - Stroupe, Carrie (Box 14)
    - Summer, Sam (Box 14)
    - Sutton, Maude, 3 folders (Box 14)
    - Sutton, Maude, 3 folders (Box 15)
    - Swaringer, R. A. (Box 15)
    - Taylor, Ida (Box 15)
    - Taylor, Louisa (Box 15)
    - Taylor, Margaret (Box 15)
    - Taylor, Mary (Box 15)
    - Teeter, Zebulon (Box 15)
    - Thomas, C. C. [Mrs.] (Box 15)
    - Thomasen, [?] (Box 15)
    - Tillet, Charles K. [Mrs.] (Box 15)
    - Thompson, Irene (Box 15)
    - Tillet, Juanita (Box 15)
    - Timmons, Lucille (Box 15)
    - Todd, Eula (Box 15)
    - Trader, William (Box 15)
    - Tucker, Grace (Box 15)
    - Tresel, W. (Box 15)
    - Trivett, Ruth (Box 15)
    - Tugman, Alex (Box 15)
    - Turner, J. K. (Box 15)
    - Turner, J. B. (Box 15)
    - Turner, Minnie (Box 15)
    - Tuttle, Ernest (Box 15)
    - Tucker, Effie (Box 15)
    - Umberger, B. L., Jr. (Box 15)
    - Vance, Ida (Box 15)
    - Vance, Zebulon [Mrs.] (Box 15)
    - Vann, Dorothy (Box 15)
    - Vann, Fanny (Box 15)
    - Vaughn, W. N. (Box 15)
    - Vaught, Gertrude (Box 15)
    - Waddell, [?] (Box 15)
    - Waggoner, T. R. (Box 15)
    - Wagoner, Lura (Box 15)
    - Walker, Edith (Box 16)
    - Walker, Elizabeth (Box 16)
    - Walker, Mary (Box 16)
    - Walker, J. P. (Box 16)
    - Wall, Martha (Box 16)
    - Wallace, C. L. (Box 16)
    - Waltz, H. O. (Box 16)
    - Ward, Monroe (Box 16)
    - Ward, Webb (Box 16)
    - Ware, R. D. (Box 16)
    - Watkins, Laura (Box 16)
    - Watkins, Sarah K. (Box 16)
    - Watson, Fawn (Box 16)
    - Watkins, Louise (Box 16)
    - Weaner, Charles (Box 16)
    - Weaver, Luna (Box 16)
    - Webb, Pearl (Box 16)
    - West Palm Beach Associated Press (Box 16)
    - White, B. N. (Box 16)
    - White, Newman (Box 16)
    - Whiteside, [?] (Box 16)
    - Whitley, Edna (Box 16)
    - Wikoff, D. (Box 16)
    - Wilkes, Robert (Box 16)
    - Wilkinson, Clarence (Box 16)
    - Williams, Crockette (Box 16)
    - Williams, E. D. (Box 16)
    - Williams, Franklin (Box 16)
    - Williams, Herbert (Box 16)
    - Williams, J. C., Jr. (Box 16)
    - Williams, Thomas (Box 16)
    - Willis, Rebecca (Box 16)
    - Wilson, Asa L. (Box 16)
    - Wilson, George (Box 16)
    - Wilson, Jim (Box 16)
    - Wilson, Leander (Box 16)
    - Wilson, Tina (Box 16)
    - Wilson, Wade (Box 16)
    - Wincherbaugh, Elaine (Box 16)
    - Winebarge, Aulcie (Box 16)
    - Winston, R. W. (Box 16)
    - Winston-Salem Journal and Sentinel (Box 16)
    - Winwar, Frances (Box 16)
    - Wister, Owen (Box 16)
    - Woodard, [?] (Box 16)
    - Woodward, [Mrs.] (Box 16)
    - Wright, J. T. Carr (Box 16)
    - Wyche, Richard (Box 16)
    - York, James (Box 16)
    - unattributed A-C (Box 17)
    - unattributed D-I (Box 17)
    - unattributed J-N (Box 17)
    - unattributed notebook (Box 17)
    - unattributed O-R (Box 17)
    - unattributed S-Z (Box 17)
  - Collected Articles and Papers Subseries, 4
    - Additional English and Scottish Ballads Found in East Tennessee. Tennessee Folklore Bulletin, Sept. 1942. Geneva Anderson. (Box 18)
    - Address to N. C. Folklore Society, undated. Frank C. Brown. 7 pp. (Box 18)
    - Adventure, 1925-1926. Clippings. Old Songs that Men Have Sung. Edited by R. W. Gorden. (Box 18)
    - American Anthology of Old World Ballads. J. Fischer & Bro., N. Y., 1937. With music. Reed Smith and Hilton Rufty. 72 pp. (Box 18)
    - American Dialect Dicitonary, The. Review by George P. Wilson, reprinted from American Speech. Dec. 1944. (Box 18)
    - American Legend in the Making. Southern Literary Messenger, May 1940. Harold Laurence Leisure. 4 pp. (Box 18)
    - American Negro Poetry. South Atlantic Quarterly, Oct. 1921. Newman I. White. 19 pp. (Box 18)
    - American-Scandinavian Review, The, July, 1914. (Box 18)
    - American Songs, Life Magazine, July 30, 1945. (Box 18)
    - American Wellerisms of the Golden Age. B. J. Whiting, reprinted from American Speech, Feb. 1945. (Box 18)
    - Annual Address to N. C. Folklore Society, Dec. 4 1936. D. T. Smithwick, Pres. 3 pp. (Box 18)
    - Another Burlesque on Addison's Ballad Criticism. Studies in Philology, Oct. 1926. R. P. McCutcheon. 6 pp. (Box 18)
    - Arran Society Folklore Prizes. Clinton, Sampson Co. Democrat, Feb. 9, 1922. 1 p. (Box 18)
    - Ballad Classification. Jeanne Y. McCauley. 17 pp. (Box 18)
    - Ballad Classification 1933. E. G. Overton. 12 pp. (Box 18)
    - Ballad Classification 1936. Mary Anne Cates. (Box 18)
    - Ballad of Jew's Daughter, "Little Sir Hugh." R. Baker Wynne. 30 pp. (Box 18)
    - Ballad Literature 1933. Mrs. E. G. Overton. 37 pp. (Box 18)
    - Ballad Literature in N. C. Proceedings, etc. of N. C. Literary and Historical Association, Dec. 1-2, 1914. Frank C. Brown. 13 pp., 2 copies; transcript (Box 18)
    - Balladry in America. Journal of American Folklore, Jan-March, 1912. H. M. Belden. 23 pp. (Box 18)
    - Ballads 1915-25. Frank C. Brown. 8pp. (Box 18)
    - Ballads. Collected and Arranged by Cecil Sharp. London: Novello and Co. 1919. Novello's School Songs. 23 pp. (Box 18)
    - Ballads and Songs. Journal of American Folklore. July-Sept 1917. G. L. Kittredge. 87 pp. (Box 18)
    - Ballads and Songs of Western N. C. Journal of American Folklore, April-June, 1909. Louise Rand Bascom. 12 pp., 2 copies (Box 18)
    - Ballads in the South. List of 41 Child Ballads reported by July 1914. Dr. C. Alphonso Smith. (Box 18)
    - Ballads Surviving in the U. S. Musical Quarterly, Jan. 1916. Dr. C. Alphonso Smith. 19 pp. (Box 18)
    - Ballet Singer, The [Mrs. Coffey]. Original poem by Mrs. Maude Minnish Sutton. 2 pp. (Box 18)
    - Barbara Allan. Edward Dreyer. 44 pp. (Box 19)
    - Barbara Allen, 1940. Kendrick S. Few. 154 pp. (Box 19)
    - Berkshire County Place Names, Their Origins and Legends, Jan. 14, 1938. Douglas Sackman. 9 pp. (Box 19)
    - Bibliography of Charms. Frank C. Brown. 5 pp. (Box 19)
    - Bibliography of Child Rhymes, etc. Frank C. Brown. 1 p. (Box 19)
    - Bibliography of Customs. Frank C. Brown. 6 pp. (Box 19)
    - Bibliography of Divination. Frank C. Brown. 3 pp. (Box 19)
    - Bibliography of Folk-Lore, 1905. Pub. For Folk-Lore Society, 1906. N. W. Thomas. 36 pp. (Box 19)
    - Bibliography of Folk Medicine. Frank C. Brown. 6 pp. (Box 19)
    - Bibliography of Housewifery. Frank C. Brown. 1 p. (Box 19)
    - Bibliography of Husbandry. Frank C. Brown. 3 pp. (Box 19)
    - Bibliography of Legends and Tales. Frank C. Brown. 9 pp. (Box 19)
    - Bibliography of Luck Signs. Frank C. Brown. 6 pp. (Box 19)
    - Bibliography of Pseudo-Science. Frank C. Brown. 2 pp. (Box 19)
    - Bibliography of Traditional Games. Frank C. Brown. 8 pp. (Box 19)
    - Bibliography of Unusual Pronunciations and Meanings. Frank C. Brown. 2 pp. (Box 19)
    - Biographical Sketch of Frank C. Brown, as prepared for Who's Who in American Education (1945-46), attached to order form. (Box 19)
    - Bird-Lore. Maybelle Poovey. 8 pp., 2 copies (Box 19)
    - Black Ox, The: A Study in the History of a Folk-Tale. Folklore Fellows Communication, Helsinki, 1927. Archer Taylor. 92 pp. (Box 19)
    - Brer Rabbit in Folk-Tales. Thomas M. N. Johnston. 21 pp., 2 copies (Box 19)
    - British Ballads in the Cumberland Mountains. Sewanee Rev., July, 1911. Rubert G. Shearin. 14 pp. (Box 19)
    - Brown Girl, The, May 25, 1938. Ruth K. Cause. 20 pp. (Box 19)
    - Brown Girl, The, May 24, 1941. Charles B. Skinner. 31 pp. (Box 19)
    - Canadian Legends, Two. J. F. Doering. 1 p. (Box 19)
    - Capstan Chanteys, Collected and Arranged by Cecil Sharp. London: Novello & Co. Novello's School Songs. 13 pp. (Box 19)
    - Cat in Myth and Folklore, The, Nov. 30, 1932. Mildred G. Tites. 9 pp. (Box 19)
    - Charms [for Tooth Ache]. Sue Hall. 1 p. (Box 19)
    - Chaucer's Love Days. Speculum, Jan. 1940. J. W. Spargo. 21 pp. (Box 19)
    - Checklist of California Songs. Department of Music, University of California, Berkeley 1940. 160 pp. (Box 19)
    - Checklist of Recorded Songs in Archive of American Folk Song, to July 1940. Library of Congress, 1942. 3 vols. 456 pp., 3 folders; 3 volumes (Box 20)
    - Cherry Tree Carol, May 17, 1935. P. Wikoff. 19 pp. (Box 20)
    - Cherry Tree Carol, Feb., 1939. Ethel M. Trus. 36 pp. (Box 20)
    - Cherry Tree Carol, May 24, 1941. W. T. Sadler, Jr. 28 pp. (Box 20)
    - Children's Singing Games I-V. Edited by Alice B. Gomme and Cecil J. Sharp. London: Novello & Co., 1909-1912. Novello's School Songs. 99 pp., 5 issues (Box 20)
    - Christmas in Mountain Song. Quarterly Magazine of Southern Industrial Educational Association, Dec. 1914. Mrs. John C. Campbell. 7 pp. (Box 20)
    - Christmas in Sweden. The National Geographic Magazine, July 1934, "Country-House Life in Sweden." 11 pp. (Box 20)
    - Christmas Lore, Jan. 19, 1934. Katherine Brooks. 29 pp. (Box 20)
    - Christmas Traditions and Customs in England. Nettie Pinnix. 30 pp. (Box 20)
    - Circular No. 1 of N. C. Folklore Society: Suggestion for Collectors. 4 pp. (Box 20)
    - Circular Letter of N. C. Folklore Society, March 12, 1941. 3 pp. (Box 20)
    - Classification of English and Scottish Popular Ballads, May 18, 1938. Ruth K. Couse. 7 pp. (Box 20)
    - Clippings. Champion YMCA Team Wins Festivity Finals (1945); N. I. White of Duke Attends Folk Festival (1945); Among the Hills our Folk Songs Thrive (1927); Folk Songs of America: Work Chanteys (1927); Combed His Hair with a Wagon Wheel (1945) (Box 20)
    - Collecting Folk Lore with Dr. Brown. Reminiscences of W. A. Abrams, in letter to Mrs. Brown, Jan. 27, 1945. (Box 20)
    - Collection of 706 Folk Beliefs. Catalogued and distributed individually throughout Collection. Anon. (Box 20)
    - Collection of Folk-Lore, The. Bulletin of Alabama. Educational Association, 1916. Newman I. White. 8 pp. (Box 20)
    - Colonel Clarke--a la Capt. Jenks. Broadside. (n.d.) (Box 20)
    - Country Dance Book, The, Part V. Edited by Cecil J. Sharp. London: Novello & Co. 51 pp. (Box 20)
    - Country Dance Society, The. Richard and Katherine Chase. New York. 3 pp. (Box 20)
    - Cruel Mother, The, May 15, 1941. Ralph A. Sheak, Jr. 21 pp. (Box 20)
    - Dan Tucker's tombstone Inscription. Typed copy. (n.d.) (Box 20)
    - Death and Burial Customs and Superstitions of the Southern Negro, Jan. 12, 1936. Lucile Pierce. 16 pp. (Box 20)
    - Death and Burial Lore, Jan. 24, 1942. Dorothy A. Luchans. 34 pp. (Box 20)
    - Death and Burial Lore in English and Scottish Popular Ballads. University of Nebraska Studies, Lincoln, Nebraska, 1927. Lowry Charles Wimberly. 138 pp. (Box 20)
    - Definitions of Folk Song. Dr. Frank C. Brown. 5 pp. (Box 21)
    - Derivation of N. C. County Names. Printed. Anon. 3 pp. (Box 21)
    - Development of the Customs and Ideas Concerning Marriage and the Family, The. Ruth K. Couse. 39 pp. (Box 21)
    - Devil As We See Him in a Few Legends and Works of Literature, The. James D. Miller. 14 pp. (Box 21)
    - Dialect and Proverbs of Mountain Folk. Mrs. Maude M. Sutton. 11 pp. (Box 21)
    - Dialect of the Folk-Song. Dialect Notes, 1916. J. H. Combs. 8 pp. (Box 21)
    - Dialects of N. C. The English Forum, High Point, May 1935. Paul Green. 2.5 pp. (Box 21)
    - Dialect Words from Western N. C. Paper before N. C. Folklore Society. Dr. George P. Wilson. 13 pp. (Box 21)
    - Divining Rod, The, Jan. 24, 1942. Pat hewitt. 15 pp. (Box 21)
    - Division of Music, Library of Congress, 1935-36, Report of, 137. (Box 21)
    - Douglas Tragedy, The. Olive Faucette. 32 pp. (Box 21)
    - Dragons, Serpents, and Smaller Reptiles. Sara Price. 14 pp. (Box 21)
    - Early English Survivals on Hatteras Island. University of N. C. Magazine, Feb. 1910, and N. C. Review, March 6, 1910. Collier Cobb. 7 pp., 2 copies (Box 21)
    - Early Witchcraft in New England. Doris Garris. 23 pp. (Box 21)
    - Easter, Jan. 19, 1934. Gertrude Garrard. 21 pp. (Box 21)
    - Edward. Mary Whitfield Canada. 61 pp. (Box 21)
    - Edward. Sue Hull. 68 pp. (Box 21)
    - Edward, 1934. LaVerne Roach. 44 pp. (Box 21)
    - Elfin Knight, The, June 28, 1936. Elizabeth Sutton. 70 pp. (Box 21)
    - European Prose Versions of Ballads in Child. Maybelle Poovey. 8 pp. (Box 21)
    - Explanation of Certain Catholic Beliefs Which Appear Superstitious, The, Jan. 24, 1934. Betty Knight. 15 pp. (Box 21)
    - Fair Margaret and Sweet Williams, May 15, 1935. W. E. Martin, Jr. 65 pp. (Box 21)
    - Fause Knight Upon the Road, The, May 17, 1936. Priscilla Smith. 29 pp. (Box 21)
    - Flower Lore. Margaret J. Phillips. 15 pp. (Box 21)
    - Folk Customs in the Blue Ridge. Maude M. Sutton, Jan. 14, 1929. (Box 21)
    - Folk Expressions--Classical Analogies. Rev. George W. Lay. 6 pp. (Box 21)
    - Folk Rhymes for Children. Clipping. New York Times Magazine, Nov. 5, 1944. (Box 21)
    - Folklore. Paper probably for N. C. Folklore Society. Frank C. Brown. 5 pp., 2 versions (Box 21)
    - Folklore, Vol. 35, No. 4, Dec. 31, 1924. (Box 21)
    - Folklore of the Dogwood. Mary Canada. 2 pp. (Box 21)
    - Folklore of Florida and Cuba. 5 pp. (Box 21)
    - Folklore Institute of America, first report, Summer Institute of Folklore, Indiana University June 29 - Aug. 22, 1942. Bloomington, Indiana, 1943. (Box 22)
    - Folklore and Minnesota History. Stith Thompson. Reprint from Minnesota History, June, 1945. (Box 22)
    - Folklore in Modern Fiction. Benice E. Rose. 27 pp. (Box 22)
    - Folklore of the Teeth. No Author. Typed, with correctiions. (n.d.) (Box 22)
    - Folklore in University Curricula in the U. S. Southern Folklore Quarterly, June, 1940. Ralph S. Boggs., 2 copies (Box 22)
    - Folklore y Nativismo en la Ensenanza Primario. Ataliva Herrera. 1945. (Box 22)
    - Folklore in Mark Twain, 1942. Leonard Beattie George, 18 pp. (Box 22)
    - Folklore in Milton's English Poems. Summary of Doct. Dies. Northwestern, 1934. Edwin Capers Kirkland. 6 pp. (Box 22)
    - Folklore in Shakespeare's Plays, 1932. Prof. T. P. Harrison. 8 pp. (Box 22)
    - Folklore of the Negro, Jan., 1942. Anne Wannamaker. 26 pp. (Box 22)
    - Folk-Lore Primer. Published by Folk-Lore Committee, Alabama Association of Teachers fo English, 1917. Newman I. White. 20 pp. (Box 22)
    - Folk-Lore Society of Texas, Publications of, No. 1, 1916. 111 pp. (Box 22)
    - Folk-Lore: Transactions of the Folk-Lore Society, for Sept. 1900, Sept 1909, March 1925, Dec. 1925, March, June and Sept. 1926, March 1927., 3 folders; 8 issues (Box 22)
    - Folk-Lore: Transactions of the Folk-Lore Society, for June, Sept. 1927, June, Sept. and Dec. 1928, March, June, Sept., Dec. 1929, March, June 1930., 4 folders; 11 issues (Box 23)
    - Folk-Song Carols. Collected and Arranged by Cecil J. Sharp. London: Novello & Co., 1913. Novello's School Songs. 11 pp. (Box 23)
    - Folk-Songs from Somerset. Collected and Arranged by Cecil J. Sharp. London: Novello & Co., 1910. Novello's School Songs. 23 pp. (Box 23)
    - Folkways in Central N. C. Questionnaire by Paul Green, through Institute for Research in Social Science. 1926? 6 pp. (Box 23)
    - Formation of N. C. Folklore Society. 6 Newspapers clippings, 1913. 1 p., clippings (Box 23)
    - Foundation of N. C. Folklore Society. Frank C. Brown. 1 p. (Box 23)
    - German Folksong, The. Sewanee Review, Jan. 1906. John S. Flory. 13 pp. (Box 23)
    - Gifts From The Ages, Jan. 24, 1934. Susan Sheppard. 19 pp. (Box 23)
    - Grand Old Ballad of Sir Patrick Spence, The. Elizabeth Powell. 45 pp. (Box 23)
    - Guyuscutus, Royal Nonesuch and Other Hoaxes, B. J. Whiting. Reprint from Southern Folklore Quarterly. Vol. 8, No. 4, Dec. 1944. (Box 23)
    - Gypsy Laddie. Olivia Womble. 48 pp. (Box 23)
    - Gypsy Laddie. Harry C. Willis. 20 pp. (Box 23)
    - Gypsie Laddie, The. Bernice E. Rose. 24 pp. (Box 23)
    - Gypsy Laddie. Constance Patten. 117 pp. (Box 24)
    - Gypsie Laddie, The. Jeanne G. McCauley. 94 pp. (Box 24)
    - Gypsie Laddie, The. Edith Herlong. 34 pp. (Box 24)
    - Gypsy Laddie, May 19, 1930. Hazel Dodgion. 13 pp. (Box 24)
    - Hallowe'en, Jan. 15, 1935. Dorothy E. Wikoff. 10 pp. (Box 24)
    - Hawaiian Hula and Some Hawaiian Folklore, The, Jan. 1, 1942. Helen Schmidt. 4 pp. (Box 24)
    - Health Superstitions. Metropolitan Life Bureau, Health Bulletin for Teachers, June, 1931. 4 pp. (Box 24)
    - Highland Annals, II Coretta and Autumn. Atlantic Monthly, June 1919. Olive Tilford Dargan. 10 pp. (Box 24)
    - Illustrated Circular of Travelling Negro Evangelist. "Rev. Dr. Hudson, D. D." 1 p. (Box 24)
    - Instructions to Collectors of Dialect. George P. Wilson. Publications of the American Dialect Society, No. 1, April 1944. (Box 24)
    - Interdisciplinary Aspects of Negro Studies, The. Bulletin 32 of American Council of Learned Societies, 1941. Melville J. Herskovitz. (Box 24)
    - Irish Folk-Drama, The. Harry C. Willis. 22 pp. (Box 24)
    - James Harris, 1937. Anon. 22 pp. (Box 24)
    - John of Hazelgreen, Ballad Study of. Gene M. Laney. 66 pp. (Box 24)
    - Johnie Scot, 1936. Emmy L. Morbon. 56 pp. (Box 24)
    - Kentucky Superstitions. Daniel and Lucy Thomas. Princeton University Press, 1920. (Box 24)
    - Kentucky Superstitions I Have Known, 1924. May Bell Kearney. 14 pp. (Box 24)
    - King Henry V's Conquest of France: Traditional Ballad Hitherto Unfound. New Jersey Journal of Education, Nov-Dec. 1930. Mellinger E. Henry. 2 pp. (Box 24)
    - Lady Alice, 1941. Arthur Rickerby. 13 pp. (Box 24)
    - Lady Isabel and the Elf-Knight. Lucy Gray Smether. 67 pp. (Box 24)
    - Lady Isabel and the Elf-Knight. Nettie Pinnix. 169 pp. (Box 25)
    - Lady Isabel and the Elf-Knight. They Brough Along Their Songs, IV, in Southern Literary Messenger, March, 1940. Frank L. Baer. 12 pp. (Box 25)
    - Lamkin--Old English Ballad. New Jersey Journal of Education, Sept. 1929. Mellinger E. Henry. 1 p. (Box 25)
    - Legends from Canada, Indiana and Florida. Southern Folklore Quarterly, Vol. 2, No. 4. 1938. J. Frederick Doering. 7 pp. (Box 25)
    - Legends of the Unicorn, Jan. 16, 1941. Dixie Swaren. 22 pp. (Box 25)
    - List of 61 Child Ballads in F. C. B. Collection. F. C. Brown. 1940. 4 pp. (Box 25)
    - Literary History of the Cat, A, Jan. 15, 1936. John Schaffner, 3rd. 8 pp. (Box 25)
    - Lord Lovel. Rubye Fogel. 40 pp. (Box 25)
    - Lord Lovel. Louise Boice. 21 pp. (Box 25)
    - Lord Lovel. Dorothy H. Greevy. 112 pp. (Box 25)
    - Lord Lovel, 1937. George Harwell. 27 pp. (Box 25)
    - Lord Randal. Jane Winters. 108 pp. (Box 25)
    - Lord Randall. Nell Trivette. 29 pp. (Box 25)
    - Lord Randall, 1938. Douglas Sackman. 14 pp. (Box 25)
    - Lord Randal. They Brought Along Their Songs III, Southern Literary Messenger, Feb., 1940. Frank L. Baer. 8 pp. (Box 25)
    - Lord Thomas and Fair Annet. Mary Anne Cates. 196 pp. (Box 25)
    - Lore of the Rose, The, Jan., 1941. Mary W. Canada. 47 pp. (Box 26)
    - MacDonald's Farmer's Almanac, 1936, Binghamton, New York. (Box 26)
    - Magic. Marie Edwards. 10 pp. (Box 26)
    - Magic. Carolyne K. Root. 10 pp. (Box 26)
    - Maid Freed From the Gallows, 1933. Maybelle Poovey. 16 pp. (Box 26)
    - Maid Freed From the Gallows, Variants of. Maybelle Poovey. 30 pp. (Box 26)
    - Maid Freed From the Gallows, 1934. Mary L. Walker. 40 pp. (Box 26)
    - Maid Freed From the Gallows, The. Rebecca Willis. 34 pp. (Box 26)
    - Maid Freed From the Gallows, The, 1942. James R. Schooley. 37 pp. (Box 26)
    - Maid Freed From the Gallows, The. Doris Garris. 36 pp. (Box 26)
    - Manuscript Book of Songs found in Newbern, N. C., during Revolution, and loaned to F. C. Brown by W. J. Andrews, Raleigh. (Box 26)
    - Marriage Ceremonies Among the Hebrews, Jan., 1943. Vivian L. Miller. 12 pp. (Box 26)
    - Marriage Customs in China and Japan. Gene Martin Laney. 20 pp. (Box 26)
    - Marriage of Sir Gawain, 1933. Carrie T. Lucas. 33 pp. (Box 26)
    - Melodic Index of Child's Ballad Tunes. Pub. University of California at Los Angeles, Berkeley, California, 1936. Sigurd Bernhard Hustuedt. 27 pp. (Box 26)
    - Mirrors of Benaboro, The, Christmas, 1925. Bruce Cotton. 36 pp. (Box 26)
    - Moon Lore, Jan. 18 (?). Priscilla Smith. 25 pp. (Box 26)
    - Motif Index of Folk Literature. Indiana University Studies, 1932-1934, Vol. 19 & 20, pp. 427; 433. Stith Thompson., 2 folders; 2 volumes (Box 26)
    - Motif Index of Folk Literature. Indiana University Studies, 1932-1934, Vol 21 & 22., pp. 411; 501. Stith Thompson., 2 folders; 2 volumes (Box 27)
    - Mountain Dance Contest and Mountain Music Festival Circular. Asheville, North Carolina, 1937. 4 pp. (Box 27)
    - Music Catalog #45, William Salloch of New York. Early editions of selected works. (n.d.) (Box 27)
    - Mythical Monsters and Their Origin. Kelvin Ray. 23 pp. (Box 27)
    - Negro and the Ballad, The. Alumni Bulletin of University of Virginia, Jan. 1913. C. Alphonso Smith. 6 pp. (Box 27)
    - Negro Singing in the 1850s. Letter of Frederika Bremer. 1 p. (Box 27)
    - New York City Folk Expressions. Anon. 4 pp. (Box 27)
    - New York Folklore Quarterly. Vol. 1, No. 1, Feb. 1945. (Box 27)
    - Nigger Blues. Le Roy White. Sheet music. Published by Bush and Gerts, Dallas, Texas, 1916. (Box 27)
    - Notes on a Guessing Game. Paul G. Brewster. Autographed. (n.d.) (Box 27)
    - North American Folklore Societies [Journal of American Folklore 56:161-191]. 1943. Wayland D. Hand. (Box 27)
    - North Carolina Dances. Mary Morrow. 11 pp. (Box 27)
    - N. C. Folklore Society Circular No. 1: Suggestions for Collectors. 4 pp. (Box 27)
    - N. C. Folklore Society Propaganda listing Child Ballads in N. C., 1920. Frank C. Brown. 6 pp. (Box 27)
    - N. C. Mountain Folk Songs: Paper before Folklore Society Dec., 1925. Mrs. M. M. Sutton. 23 pp. (Box 27)
    - N. C. Parallels to Newell's Games and Songs. Jennie Belvin. 7 pp. (Box 27)
    - North Carolina Place Names. Ellerbe Powe, Jr. (Box 27)
    - Omens and Magic in The Canterbury Tales. Mary L. Walker. 19 pp. (Box 27)
    - Origin and Celebration of Mardi Gras in Mobile, The. Alexina Demouy. 22 pp. (Box 27)
    - Origin of the Belief in Fairies and the Present Status of Fairies in Various Countries, The. Jeanne Y. McCauley. 57 pp. (Box 27)
    - Organization Circular of N. C. Folklore Society, 1913-1914. 4 pp., 2 issues (Box 27)
    - Origins of Expressions, Terms and Customs. Mary L. Walker. 24 pp. (Box 27)
    - Our Goodman, 1934. Katherine Brooks. 18 pp. (Box 27)
    - Our Satellite. Crockette Williams. 19 pp. (Box 27)
    - Part Rabbits Play in Folklore, The. Jan. 11, 1935. Louise Boice. 16 pp. (Box 27)
    - Partial List of Persons and Organizations Interested in Folklore from Folklore Americas, Dec. 1944. pp. 9-19. Ralph S. Boggs. (Box 27)
    - Patrol Regulations for the Town of Tarborough. Broadside. (N.C.) 1837. (Box 27)